Next, let's learn how to make a beret.
First, create a single plate with the previous sheep, and copy them to 6.
This time, because we have copied 6, we can select them directly, and then set them as linked plates.
Then, use the line sewing tool to sew their sides together.
For convenience, we can first freeze the plate in front of us in the middle,
and turn on the other plates to simulate them automatically, and then activate the plate to simulate them together.
It's the same as making a baseball cap just now, and now we're going to print the whole plate.
Press the W key and click the plate, and you can create a pin on the plate to fix it.
Then, without the key, you can press the W key, and you can create a pin on the plate to fix it.
Now, in the case of starting the simulation, select these plates, and drag them up a little with the square wheel.
Then, when we start the simulation, you can see that the plate is fixed in the 3D window.
Then, we can make a adjustment to these plates.
First of all, berets and suretees have a characteristic.
The hat at the top here will expand outwards first, and then close the bottom of the hat at the end.
So, we are on the left and right sides.
Add two straight points to each side close to the bottom
Then pull them out a little bit with the edit board tool
After pulling it out, because they are all linked boards
After opening the simulation, our modification will be applied to the board
Now they look more like our common beret hat
Then we pull the bottom white down a little bit
Make the thickness of his hat thicker
Because the separation point of the beret hat adjustment is the widest point on both sides
So if you want his top here to be more loose
Then you can move the top point up a little bit
If you want it to be more loose, you can move it up a little bit
This is the effect we want to achieve by modifying the board
After that, we can see that he is in the corner
Then we can see that he is in the corner
This position is very sharp
This is because we have sharp corners here
So we are going to use the circular curve tool
Turn the corners on both sides into round corners
After that, we can start to prepare the head band
Because the beret hat is not like other hats
The whole can be covered in the head
It's not slippery or slippery
So the easiest way to make it is to make the band first
Then fix the band near the model
Then make the adjustment after that
Draw a width of about three times the model's head
Then the height of the rectangular shape at will
And press the CTRL D to create a symmetrical board
Then use the line powder tool to sew the two sides together
After sewing, to ensure the stability of the simulation
Reduce the strength of the plate first
Reduce the range
Reduce the thickness of the collision
And press SHIFT F to put the board near the head of the virtual model
After opening the simulation
The board will be sewn together automatically
But they can't be fixed very well near the virtual model
And here we can see that this board is a bit narrow
So we have to pull it a little wider
At this time, after opening the simulation
We will find that as long as we drag the board
This board will still slide out of the model's head
So we copy a piece of fabric first
And give these two newly created boards new fabric
In the process of our movement
You can also find that this board is still a bit narrow
So let's make it a little wider
Then we rearrange this board
After arranging, we will widen this board
In order to fix the front end of the board
So that we can adjust it conveniently
Here we are going to use the function of fixing to virtual model
Click the board to the center
Then click the front position of the virtual model's forehead
After that, our board is fixed to the front
We just need to drag the board in the state of opening the simulation
So that it can hang very well near the virtual model's forehead
That's it
The eyebrows and eyelashes part
Because the grid is relatively small
So it's easier to hook the board
Then we can adjust it
If you can't adjust it
You can use the selection grid tool
Pull out their grid separately
After almost hanging on the head
We can make a adjustment to the physical properties of the board
First of all, we put the fabric
To increase the friction
So that the fabric will not slide anymore
That is to say
When we are adjusting the position of the fabric
It is also relatively easy to fix in the position of our adjustment
Then just in the process of our adjustment
Will find that this tape
It can't stick to the head very well
It's because its bending strength is too high
It's too hard
After we reduce the bending strength
It can stick better to the head
It's all good
After that
We can adjust the position of this tie
We can adjust the position of the tie
After we reduce the bending strength
After adjusting the position of the forehead
Will find that its length is a little long
So let's reduce its width a little bit here
Because now the model is not visible to the black and white surface
So we can switch the color of this fabric to black
Convenient for us to identify
After changing the color, we will find that the hair band and the hair are a bit different
This is because the particle diameter of our hair band is not low enough
Then the surface diameter and the thickness of the collision are relatively low
So now the two nets are too close
Because the hat is definitely close to the human body
So here we can only reduce the particle diameter to 5
That's ok
Finally, we merge the front and the back here
Then adjust the position of the fake sewing needle
Merging is to make this bag look like a whole
For the fake sewing needle, we choose red here
If you move the red dot up a little
You can sew the real bag to the top of the head of the sewing needle
Now that we have adjusted it, we can freeze this plate
No longer move it
Because the frozen plate
Although it can collide with other plates
But its shape will not change
After that, in the case of not opening the model
Use the positioning ball tool to choose the plate of this hat
Then move them to the area of ​​this plate
Then use the line sewing tool
First choose the complete line at the bottom
Then press the SHIFT key to fill
From left to right, sew the half of the plate
Then the other half is also the same operation
After sewing
Open the simulation
After opening the simulation
Dissolve the hardening
And delete the fixed needle
The method of deleting the fixed needle is very simple
After selecting the fixed needle
You can delete it by pressing the DELETE key
After that, we can give the main fabric of the hat here
Change a pre-set
Pre-set attribute select wool
Wool is wool
That is the kind of fabric we often use
Reduce the particle diameter of the plate first
Make its fold more detailed
And reduce its contact thickness to 1
After that, we can manually drag this point
Let the hat form an effect of leaning to one side
It looks more real
If you want to adjust its width and width
You can adjust it now
If we put the top point up
If we pull the top point up
After that
It will also be slightly arched
In this way
Through our continuous drag and drag
Can make it form a relatively
The effect of a puffy beret hat
If you want to make an artist hat
Or a painter hat
Its top is usually not so puffy
This ridiculous animation
Let us draw a picture to see
That's OK
OK
If this happens
We can pull down the top point a little bit
If we pull the sides of the play
A little bit
We can see that the fabric of this hat is more
It looks better
In the process of adjustment, the distribution of the fold is not very satisfied, but if it is not convenient to adjust again, we can directly select these panels and print them, print them, and then remove them.
After the removal, we can use it as a reference to adjust again.
After being printed, we can first control the direction of the fold, and then remove the print to manually adjust them.
In addition, because the length of the belt we tied is different from the hat itself,
so the hat will produce some folds along the seam line here.
It will also look more real.
Next, we can apply a elastic to this edge along the seam line.
The ratio of the elastic can be set to 98 or 95.
After setting the elastic ratio, there will be more folds along this line.
If 98 is not very obvious,
we can adjust the value a little bit and set it to 95.
Finally, reduce the particle diameter to 5 and start the simulation.
In this way, the details will be more obvious.
Finally, after we have manually adjusted the effect of the panel,
we can add a dot here in the way of adding a twist.
If you think that the effect of this side is not very consistent with the effect we want,
we can freeze other panels first.
Then activate this side.
After activating it,
reverse-activate the virtual model and then select this side.
After selecting it,
we first set the angle of its floating line.
Just like the baseball cap before, set the fold angle to 0.
After setting to 0,
turn on the simulation and it will automatically turn in.
After turning, I think there is a dot here.
It is below the seam line.
So no matter how we pull it, it will turn down.
So here we use the edit seam tool to delete this seam line.
Finally, press Shift A to display the virtual model and turn on the simulation.
After the model is stable, all our panels are finished.
Thank you for watching.
See you next time.
Bye bye.